export const GEOGRAPHYA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. What is the contour interval of the map?",
A: "50 m",
B: "100 m",
C: "150 m",
D: "400 m",
answer: "B. 100 m",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. What is the scale of the map in statement form?",
A: "One centimetre on the map represents half kilometre on the ground",
B: "One centimetre on the map represents one kilometre on the ground",
C: "One centimetre on the map represents five kilometres on the ground",
D: "One centimetre on the map represents fifteen kilometres on the ground",
answer: "A. One centimetre on the map represents half kilometre on the ground",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The approximate length of river ofon is",
A: "18.3 km.",
B: "16.5 km.",
C: "6.5 km.",
D: "3.0 km",
answer: "C. 6.5 km.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following settlements is nodal?",
A: "Beace",
B: "Hop",
C: "proga",
D: "NITY",
answer: "D. NITY",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The highest elevation in the mapped area is approximately",
A: "800 m.",
B: "900 m.",
C: "1250 m.",
D: "1400 m.",
answer: "C. 1250 m.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. What is the relief feature marked x?",
A: "Ridge",
B: "Plateau",
C: "Knoll",
D: "Gorge",
answer: "C. Knoll",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. If the map of NITY DISTRICT is reduced to half, what will be the scale of the map in Representative Fraction (FR)?",
A: "1:25,000",
B: "1:50,000",
C: "1: 100,000",
D: "1:150,000",
answer: "C. 1: 100,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The relief feature on the west of NITY, which extends to the north-western corner of the map is a",
A: "gorge.",
B: "plain.",
C: "plateau.",
D: "ridge.",
answer: "D. ridge.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. In which settlement is mining practised in the mapped area?",
A: "NITY",
B: "Hop",
C: "Coura",
D: "Proga",
answer: "C. Coura",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Where can civil conflicts be resolved in the district?",
A: "Proga",
B: "Coura",
C: "Hop",
D: "NITY",
answer: "D. NITY",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following statistical methods is represented above?",
A: "Dot map",
B: "Isohaline map",
C: "Flowmap",
D: "Bar chart",
answer: "C. Flowmap",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. How many passengers travelled between IZABU and Ashama?",
A: "6,000",
B: "8,000",
C: "10,000",
D: "12,000",
answer: "D. 12,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. By how much is the traffic between IZABU and Anikpu more than the traffic between IZABU and Ugba?",
A: "1,200",
B: "1,500",
C: "1,700",
D: "1,800",
answer: "B. 1,500",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. One major advantage of the figure is that, it",
A: "is easy to construct.",
B: "shows quantity and direction together.",
C: "is easy to interpret.",
D: "involves mathematical calculation",
answer: "A. is easy to construct.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The density of the earth’s crust varies from",
A: "17.0 to 19.5 g/cm3.",
B: "8.0 to 10.9 g/cm3.",
C: "4.5 to 7.0 g/cm3.",
D: "2.5 to 3.3 g/cm3.",
answer: "D. 2.5 to 3.3 g/cm3",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following features is found in the upper course of a river?",
A: "Levee",
B: "Gorge",
C: "Ox-bow lake",
D: "Delta",
answer: "B. Gorge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following elements of climate is used in the Greek system of climatic classification?",
A: "Rainfall",
B: "Pressure",
C: "Humidity",
D: "Temperature",
answer: "D. Temperature",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Two opposite longitudes form",
A: "a Great Circle.",
B: "the Equator.",
C: "the International Date Line.",
D: "the Arctic Circle.",
answer: "A. a Great Circle.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. What is the local time in Town X 45oE, when it is noon at 0°?",
A: "6.00 pm",
B: "8.00 am",
C: "3.00 pm",
D: "3.00 am",
answer: "C. 3.00 pm",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following examples of igneous rock is extrusive?",
A: "Granite",
B: "Basalt",
C: "Gabbro",
D: "Diorite",
answer: "B. Basalt",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Rift valleys are formed through which of the following processes?",
A: "Erosion",
B: "Folding",
C: "Weathering",
D: "Faulting",
answer: "D. Faulting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Caverns, dry valleys and underground drainage are associated with which of the following a",
A: "Coastal",
B: "Desert",
C: "Limestone",
D: "Mountainous",
answer: "C. Limestone",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following processes of wind action is erosion?",
A: "Saltation",
B: "Deflation",
C: "Suspension",
D: "Traction",
answer: "B. Deflation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. From what are carbonaceous type of sedimentary rocks made of?",
A: "Tropical heat",
B: "Molten magma",
C: "Vegetable matter",
D: "Coral remains",
answer: "D. Coral remains",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following is a drainage pattern?",
A: "Delta",
B: "Mouth",
C: "Source",
D: "Trellis",
answer: "D. Trellis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The predominant process of weathering in the desert regions is",
A: "biological.",
B: "chemical.",
C: "physical.",
D: "solution.",
answer: "C. physical.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The instrument barometer, is used for measuring",
A: "temperature.",
B: "wind speed.",
C: "relative humidity.",
D: "air pressure.",
answer: "D. air pressure.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which climatic type has winter rain?",
A: "Equatorial",
B: "Mediterranean",
C: "Tropical Continental",
D: "Tropical Monsoon",
answer: "B. Mediterranean",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following igneous intrusions is horizontally inclined?",
A: "Sill",
B: "Dyke",
C: "Laccolith",
D: "Batholith",
answer: "A. Sill",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following rocks is not metamorphic?",
A: "Shale",
B: "Schist",
C: "Quartzite",
D: "Slate",
answer: "A. Shale",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. If the temperature reading at an observatory located on top of a dormant volcano is 6°C. what will be the temperature at the bottom of the volcano. if the observatory is 3.000 metres from the surrounding lowland?",
A: "5.5°C",
B: "13.5°C",
C: "25.5°C",
D: "35.5°C",
answer: "B. 13.5°C",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A crescentic depositional feature found in a desert area is",
A: "rock pedestal.",
B: "zeugen.",
C: "yardang.",
D: "barchan dune.",
answer: "D. barchan dune.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is not a volcanic feature?",
A: "Caldera",
B: "Geyser",
C: "Dyke",
D: "Ventifact",
answer: "D. Ventifact",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Earth’s surface is warmed by solar energy through",
A: "refraction.",
B: "convection.",
C: "conduction.",
D: "radiation.",
answer: "D. radiation.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Vosges and Black Forest mountains are examples of",
A: "residual.",
B: "block.",
C: "fold.",
D: "volcanic.",
answer: "A. residual.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. How many Standard Time Zones will a country with longitudinal extent of 150o have?",
A: "10",
B: "11",
C: "15",
D: "16",
answer: "A. 10",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. One important consequence of the location of Nigeria between latitudes 4o and 14o North of the Equator is that",
A: "the northern part of the country enjoys land and sea breezes.",
B: "all parts of the country receive rainfall throughout the year.",
C: "all parts of the country have luxuriant vegetation.",
D: "some parts of the country enjoy a hot, wet tropical climate three times a year.",
answer: "C. all parts of the country have luxuriant vegetation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Subsistence farming is practised when people",
A: "grow crops for consumption.",
B: "grow only one crop.",
C: "export only one crop.",
D: "grow many crops for export.",
answer: "A. grow crops for consumption.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following factors hinder the development of tourism? I. Spread of diseases II. Escalation of crime III. Adequate publicity IV. Inadequate appreciation of leisure",
A: "I and III only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I and IV only",
D: "III and IV only",
answer: "C. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The busiest ocean trade route is the",
A: "Mozambique channel.",
B: "Suez Canal route.",
C: "North Atlantic route.",
D: "Cape rout",
answer: "C. North Atlantic route",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "C. linear.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The major causes of change in population size are:",
A: "births, marriage and deaths.",
B: "births, accidents and deaths.",
C: "births, deaths and migration.",
D: "migration, fertility and marriage.",
answer: "C. births, deaths and migration.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Banking, insurance and teaching are examples of which industry",
A: "Consumer",
B: "Tertiary",
C: "Secondary",
D: "Primary",
answer: "B. Tertiary",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A rapid population growth can result from",
A: "high death and low birth rate.",
B: "the use of family planning methods.",
C: "absence of natural hazards.",
D: "improved medical care.",
answer: "A. high death and low birth rate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The term relative location of a settlement refers to",
A: "the nature of the land on which the settlement is located.",
B: "the position of a settlement in relation to others.",
C: "a settlement inhabited by relatives.",
D: "an imaginary point on a settlement.",
answer: "B. the position of a settlement in relation to others.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Transportation helps economic development through all the following except",
A: "movement of people and commodities.",
B: "promotion of national and international trade.",
C: "diffusion of ideas and technology.",
D: "distribution of human population.",
answer: "C. diffusion of ideas and technology.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Most industries in West African sub-region are",
A: "large-scale",
B: "small-scale",
C: "medium-scale",
D: "capital intensive",
answer: "B. small-scale",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following areas in Tropical Africa is densely populated?",
A: "South-western Nigeria",
B: "The middle belt of West Africa",
C: "The Sahel region of West Africa",
D: "The Niger Delta",
answer: "D. The Niger Delta",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. What is the sum total of human resources available in a country called?",
A: "Cluster",
B: "Inhabitants",
C: "Population",
D: "Primary",
answer: "C. Population",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The predominance of consumer-oriented industries in developing countries is accounted for by",
A: "limited demand.",
B: "adequate capital.",
C: "limited skilled manpower.",
D: "high level of technology.",
answer: "C. limited skilled manpower",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]